<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE root SYSTEM "MedTxt.dtd">
<root>
<metadata>
<name>MedTxt-RR</name>
<dataset>training</dataset>
<language>EN</language>
<creator>Sociocom</creator>
<version>1.0</version>
<release-date>2021-09-30</release-date>
<origin>https://sociocom.naist.jp/</origin>
</metadata>
<articles>
<article id="0" title="03">
There is <d certainty="positive">consolidation</d> <a>along the bronchial area</a> in the <a>left lingual segment</a>. <a>Internally</a> accompanied by <d certainty="positive">bronchiectasis</d> and <d certainty="positive">pleural invagination</d> <a>around</a> the <d certainty="positive">consolidation</d>. There is no contradiction with the <d certainty="positive">lung cancer</d> you observed.
The size of the <d certainty="positive">lesion</d> is <f>28 mm</f>, which is considered to be equivalent to <d>T1c</d>.
</article>
<article id="1" title="09">
There is an <d certainty="positive">infiltrative shadow</d> <a>along the bronchial area of the lower lobe of the right lung</a>, which is considered to be <d certainty="positive">lung cancer</d>.
It is in <a>wide contact with the interlobar pleura</a>, and is considered to be <d certainty="positive">pleural infiltration</d>.
The <a>right middle bronchus</a> is <d certainty="positive">obstructed</d> by a <d certainty="positive">mass</d>. <f>Extensive</f> <d certainty="positive">ground glass shadows</d> are found in the <a>lower lobe of the right lung</a>, and it appears <d certainty="positive">obstructive pneumonia</d> is present.
There also appears to be <d certainty="positive">infiltration</d> of the <a>right pulmonary artery, right pulmonary vein, and aortic arch</a>.
There is a <d certainty="positive">nodular shadow</d> in the <a>upper lobe of the right lung</a>, but <c>no change</c>.
<d certainty="positive">Lymphadenopathy</d> in the <a>right hilar, ipsilateral mediastinum, contralateral mediastinum, contralateral hilar, and left supraclavicular fossa</a> is considered to indicate <d certainty="positive">metastatic lymph nodes</d>.
There are <d certainty="positive">multiple masses</d> on the <a>skin, liver, and right adrenal gland</a>, which are considered to be <d certainty="positive">multiple metastases</d>.
Based on the above, it is likely <d certainty="positive">lung cancer</d> (<d>ｃT4N3M1ｃ</d>).
</article>
<article id="2" title="12">
There is some <d certainty="positive">blurring</d> and it is a <f>poor study</f>.
<f>Diffuse</f> <d certainty="positive">multiple nodules</d> are found in <a>both lungs</a>. <f>Partial</f> <d certainty="positive">mass-like opacities</d> are also observed on the <a>mediastinal side of the lower right lobe</a>, but if it is a <f>unified</f> <d certainty="suspicious">lung cancer lesion</d>, then <f>multiple</f> <d certainty="suspicious">mucin-producing adenocarcinomas</d> are suspected (<d>T4</d>).
<f>Significant</f> <d certainty="negative">mediastinal lymphadenopathy</d> cannot be pointed out.
No <f>significant</f> <d certainty="negative">pleural effusion</d> is observed.
<f>Multiple</f> <d certainty="positive">osteogenic masses</d> are found in the <a>thoracic spine</a> and may <d certainty="suspicious">metastasize</d> (<d>M1c</d>).
The <a>liver</a> shows a <f>blunt edge</f> and suggests <d certainty="positive">chronic liver damage</d>, but no <f>coarse</f> <d certainty="negative">mass</d> can be noted.
No <f>obvious</f> <d certainty="negative">mass</d> can be noted in the <a>adrenal glands</a>.
</article>
<article id="3" title="03">
An <d certainty="positive">irregular mass lesion</d> of <f>approximately 28 mm</f> is seen, with the <f>main part</f> <a>centred on the outside of the left lung lingular segment S4</a>. The <a>interior</a> is <f>occupied</f> by <d certainty="positive">infiltration shadows and ground-glass shadowing</d>, and an <d certainty="positive">expanded image</d> <f>partly</f> remains in the <a>bronchioles</a>. Suspect <d certainty="suspicious">minimally invasive adenocarcinoma</d> with a <f>predominant lepidic growth pattern</f>.There is also a <d certainty="positive">linear shadow</d> on the <a>margin</a> that <a>connects to the pleura</a>, but we suspect the presence of <d certainty="suspicious">inflammatory scars and fibrous changes</d>.Based on impression, <a>pleural</a> <d certainty="negative">infiltration</d> is not suspected. <r state="other">Surgical treatment</r> seems possible.
</article>
<article id="4" title="06">
[<t-test state="executed">CT scan of the chest with contrast</t-test>]
A <f>15 mm large</f> <d certainty="positive">nodule</d> is seen in the <a>lower lobe of the right lung</a>, <d certainty="positive">obstructing</d> the <a>trachea of the lower right lobe</a>. There is <d certainty="positive">atelectasis</d> of the <a>lower lobe of the right lung</a>.
In addition, the <a>subcarinal lymph nodes</a> are <d certainty="positive">swollen</d> to <f>22 mm in size</f>, and <d certainty="positive">multiple tumours</d> are also seen in the <a>mediastinal lymph nodes on both sides and the left supraclavicular node</a>.
Based on the above, <d certainty="suspicious">lung cancer and multiple lymph node tumours</d> are suspected.
No <d certainty="negative">tumours</d> are seen in the <a>liver, adrenal glands, or bone</a>.
There is a <d certainty="positive">decrease</d> in the <a>Th7 vertebral body</a>, and <d certainty="suspicious">compression fracture</d> is suspected.
</article>
<article id="5" title="09">
A <f>43 mm</f> <d certainty="positive">irregular mass</d> <c>appears</c> in the <a>lower lobe of the right lung</a>, <a>mainly in the hilar region</a>, and is accompanied by <a>bronchial</a> <d certainty="positive">stenosis</d>. It is without consistencies as known <d certainty="positive">lung cancer</d> (<d>T2b</d>). For the <d certainty="positive">shadow</d> on the <a>peripheral side</a>, first consider <d certainty="suspicious">obstructive pneumonia</d>, but please <cc state="other">follow the morphology</cc> to exclude <d certainty="suspicious">metastasis</d>.
A <d certainty="positive">tubercle</d> is found in the <a>upper lobe of the right lung</a> <a>just below the pleura</a>, but it has been seen <timex3 type="date">for 10 years</timex3> and is considered to be an <d certainty="positive">old-fashioned inflammatory change</d>.
Other <f>obvious</f> <d certainty="negative">abnormal shadows</d> cannot be identified in the <a>lung field</a>.
<f>Numerous</f> <d certainty="positive">pathological lymphadenopathy</d> is found in the <a>right hilum, tracheal bifurcation, and ipsilateral / contralateral mediastinum</a>, suggesting <d certainty="positive">multiple lymphadenopathy</d> (<d>N3</d>).
<f>Many</f> <d certainty="positive">low-absorption masses</d> are found in the <a>liver</a>, suggesting <d certainty="positive">multiple liver metastases</d>.
The <a>right adrenal gland</a> is <d certainty="positive">swollen</d> and may also <d certainty="suspicious">metastasize</d>.
<f>Numerous</f> <d certainty="positive">nodular shadows</d> are also found on the <a>chest wall and in the breast</a>, and these may also be <d certainty="suspicious">metastasized</d> unitarily (<d>M1c</d>).
No <f>significant</f> <d certainty="negative">pleural effusion</d> is observed.
</article>
<article id="6" title="12">
We observed an <f>approximately x cm</f> <d certainty="positive">neoplastic lesion accompanying spicula as well as tightening of the pleura</d> in the <a>interior of the right lower lobe</a>. <d certainty="suspicious">Primary lung cancer</d> is suspected.
We observed <f>diffuse</f> <d certainty="positive">micronodules and nodules</d> in <a>both lungs</a>. We suspect <d certainty="suspicious">multiple metastases</d> across <a>both lungs</a>.
There is <d certainty="positive">swelling in the lymph nodes</d> across the <a>right pulmonary hilum and mediastinum</a>, and <d certainty="suspicious">metastases to the lymph nodes</d> is suspected.
We observed <d certainty="positive">osteosclerotic shadowing</d> across the <a>eight to eleventh thoracic vertebrae columns</a>. <d certainty="suspicious">Osteosclerotic bone metastases</d> are suspected.
</article>
<article id="7" title="06">
In the <a>right hilar region</a>, a <d certainty="positive">tumour</d> with an <f>unclear border</f> is seen and has become a <f>mass</f> with the <d certainty="positive">lymph nodes</d>. The <d certainty="suspicious">contrast effect</d> is <f>unknown</f>, and the size and <a>boundaries</a> are <f>unclear</f>. It is likely <d certainty="positive">lung cancer</d>.
The <a>right middle and lower lobe bronchus</a> are <d certainty="positive">occluded</d> and the <a>nearby lumen</a> is <f>irregular</f>. It may be <d certainty="positive">tumour infiltration</d>.
The <a>middle lobe</a> is <d certainty="positive">atelectic</d> and the <a>lower lobe of the right lung</a> is <f>completely</f> <c>collapsed</c>.
The T factor is considered to be <d>T2</d>.
<d certainty="negative">Lesions suspected of lung metastasis</d> cannot be identified.
<f>Multiple</f> <d certainty="positive">pathological swollen lymph nodes</d> are seen in the <a>mediastinum and left supraclavicular fossa</a>.
The N factor is considered to be <d>N3</d>.
There is no <d certainty="negative">pleural effusion</d>.
No <d certainty="negative">bone destruction</d> <f>strongly indicating bone metastasis or mass lesions</f> are observed in the <a>imaging range</a>.
Other M factors cannot be determined and are <d>MX</d>.
</article>
<article id="8" title="12">
<f>Numerous</f> <f>irregular</f> <d certainty="positive">nodules</d> are present in the <a>bilateral lung fields</a>. It looks like a <f>random distribution</f>.
The <f>primary</f> <d certainty="positive">lung cancer</d> is unclear, but it is considered to be a <f>combination</f> of a <d certainty="positive">primary tumour</d> and <f>numerous</f> <d certainty="positive">metastases</d>.
The T factor is considered to be <d>T4</d>.
There are no <d certainty="negative">pathologically enlarged lymph nodes</d> in the <a>hilum, mediastinum or supraclavicular fossa</a>.
The N factor is considered to be <d>N0</d>.
There is no <d certainty="negative">pleural effusion</d>.
There is no evidence of <d certainty="negative">metastatic lesions</d> in the <a>liver or adrenal glands in the imaging area</a>.
The <a>liver</a> has an <f>uneven and irregular surface</f> and is considered to be <d certainty="positive">cirrhotic</d>.
A <f>ground-glass</f> like <d certainty="positive">osteosclerotic image</d> of the <a>8th-11th thoracic vertebrae</a> is present and <d certainty="suspicious">metastasis</d> is suspected.
<d certainty="positive">Osteosclerosis</d> is also seen in the <a>upper thoracic and lumbar vertebrae endplates</a>, which may be <d certainty="suspicious">metastatic or degenerative</d>.
The M factor is considered to be <d>M1c</d>.
</article>
<article id="9" title="13">
A <d certainty="positive">lobular mass lesion</d> with a <f>major axis of 7.8 cm</f> and a <f>well-defined margin</f> is seen <a>centering on the S9/10 region</a> of the <a>lower lobe of the left lung</a>. The <a>inside</a> is <f>solid</f>, but <f>some</f> <d certainty="positive">air</d> is present, and it appears to be a <d certainty="positive">cavitary lesion</d>. <d certainty="positive">Ground-glass shadows</d> can also be seen <a>around</a> it. <d certainty="suspicious">Primary lung cancer</d> is suspected. <f>Multiple</f> <d certainty="positive">nodular shadows and mass shadows</d> can be seen on the <a>central side</a> of the lesion. They are distributed <a>along the bronchial vascular bundles</a> in the <a>lower lobe of the left lung</a>, with <f>lymphatic</f> <d certainty="positive">infiltration</d>. The <d certainty="positive">lesion</d> <d certainty="positive">invades</d> the <a>mediastinum from the left hilum</a>. <d certainty="positive">Metastasis to the left hilar and mediastinal lymph nodes</d> are seen.
There are no <d certainty="negative">suspected intrapulmonary metastases</d> in the <a>contralateral lung</a>.
No <d certainty="negative">lesions that suggest bone metastasis</d> can be identified <a>within the observable range</a>.
</article>
<article id="10" title="09">
We observe an <f>approximately 4.3 x 3.8 cm sized</f> <d certainty="positive">neoplastic lesion</d> <f>continuing</f> from the <a>pulmonary hilum to the right lower lobe</a>. There is <d certainty="positive">invasion</d> into the <a>bronchus of the right lower lobe, the pulmonary arteries, etc</a>. <d certainty="suspicious">Primary lung cancer</d> is suspected. We observe <f>several</f> <d certainty="positive">nodule shadows</d> in the <a>right lower lobe</a>. We suspect these to be <d certainty="positive">lung metastases</d>.
<d certainty="positive">Constriction</d> of the <a>right lower lobe bronchi</a> can be seen. We observe an <d certainty="positive">area of increased density with a ground-glass like appearance</d> in the <a>right lower lobe</a>. Along with the <d certainty="positive">constriction of the bronchi</d>, there was a <d certainty="suspicious">partially collapsed lung, and adjoint pneumonia</d> is suspected.
In the <a>exterior S1 layer of the right upper lobe</a> there were observed <d certainty="positive">nodule shadows</d>, but these were also seen in <timex3 type="date">past</timex3> <t-test state="executed">CT scans</t-test> and there has been <c>no change</c>. It is suspected that these are <d certainty="suspicious">benign nodular lesions</d>, and they do not appear to be <d certainty="negative">lung metastases</d>.
There is observed <d certainty="positive">multiple lymphatic swellings</d> <f>continuing</f> from the <a>right pulmonary hilum to the superior mediastinum</a>. We suspect <d certainty="suspicious">multiple lymphatic metastases</d>.
There were observed <f>small and large</f> <d certainty="positive">neoplastic lesions</d> in <a>both breasts</a> and there is a possibility of <d certainty="suspicious">metastases to the mammary glands</d>.
There were also seen <d certainty="positive">several nodular shadows</d> in the <a>liver</a>. These <d certainty="positive">neoplastic lesions</d> had <f>little</f> <d certainty="negative">enhancement</d>, and are suspected to be <d certainty="suspicious">multiple liver metastases</d>.
We also observed <d certainty="positive">neoplastic shadows</d> in the <a>right adrenal glands</a>. We suspect <d certainty="suspicious">adrenal metastases</d>.
There is <d certainty="positive">swelling</d> in the <a>lymph nodes of the hepatic portal, the lesser curvature of the stomach, and the area surrounding the aorta</a>. We suspect <d certainty="suspicious">lymphatic metastases</d>.
We observed <d certainty="positive">renal cysts</d>.
We did not find any <f>significant</f> observations regarding the <a>gallbladder, pancreas, or spleen</a>.
We observed <d certainty="positive">nodule shadows</d> in the <a>subcutaneous region of the right abdominal wall</a>.
We do not observe any <f>clear</f> <d certainty="negative">osteolytic or osteoblastic tumors</d> in the <a>bones</a>. There are no <d certainty="negative">findings leading us to suspect metastases of the bones</d>.
</article>
<article id="11" title="13">
A <d certainty="positive">mass lesion with a cavity</d> with a <f>length of 78 mm</f> was seen <a>mainly in the lower left lobe S9</a>, which is considered to be the known <d certainty="positive">cancer</d>. The <d certainty="positive">contact</d> with the <a>pleura</a> is <f>strong</f>, and <d certainty="suspicious">infiltration</d> cannot be denied. <d certainty="positive">Nodular shadows and ground-glass shadows</d> <a>along the bronchi</a> are also <f>widespread</f> on the <a>central side</a>, which is considered to be a <f>unified</f> <d certainty="positive">neoplastic lesion</d> (<d>T4</d>).
<d certainty="positive">Emphysematous changes</d> are observed on the <a>background of the lung field</a>.
<d certainty="positive">Pathological swelling</d> is <f>occasionally seen</f> in the <a>subcarinal lymph node</a> and <d certainty="positive">ipsilateral mediastinal/hilar lymph nodes</d>, suggesting <d certainty="positive">metastasis</d> (<d>N2</d>).
No <f>significant</f> <d certainty="negative">pleural effusion</d> is observed.
</article>
<article id="12" title="03">
A <d certainty="positive">tumour</d> with <f>a diameter of 28 mm</f> and a <f>pleural indentation</f> is seen in the <a>upper right lobe S3</a>. An <d certainty="positive">air bronchogram</d> is <a>inside</a>, and the <a>border</a> has a <d certainty="positive">ground-glass shadow</d>. It seems to be a lesion corresponding to a <d certainty="suspicious">part-solid GGN</d>. <d certainty="suspicious">Lepidic predominant adenocarcinoma (LPA)</d> is suspected. It seems to be equivalent to <d>T1c</d> in T classification.
The <a>lower right lobe S6</a> also has a <d certainty="positive">nodule</d> with a <f>small</f> <f>interlobar pleural indentation</f>. <d certainty="suspicious">Lung cancer</d> cannot be ruled out here either, but it is difficult to distinguish it from <d certainty="suspicious">inflammatory nodules</d>. Please take a <t-test state="other">biopsy</t-test> or <cc state="other">monitor closely</cc>. No other <d certainty="negative">lesions suspected to be accessory tumour nodules</d> can be seen in the <a>lung field</a>.
No <f>round</f> <d certainty="negative">lymphadenopathy</d> can be seen that may be <d certainty="negative">metastasised</d> to the <a>supraclavicular fossa, hilar region, or mediastinum</a>.
No <d certainty="negative">pleural effusion</d> is observed.
No <f>significant</f> abnormality can be identified in the <a>upper abdominal organs in the imaging range</a>.
</article>
<article id="13" title="09">
There is a <f>large 43mm</f> <d certainty="positive">tumor</d> <f>occupying</f> the <a>right hilum</a>. This is considered to be the known <d certainty="positive">lung cancer</d>.
In addition, a <d certainty="positive">mass</d> that appeared to be a <d certainty="suspicious">satellite lesion</d> was observed in the <a>lower lobe of the right lung</a>. There were also <d certainty="positive">nodules</d> <a>inside the trachea of the lower right lung</a> and a <d certainty="positive">ground glass-like concentration</d> in the <a>lower lobe of the right lung</a>.This may also indicate <d certainty="suspicious">tumor development</d>.
<d certainty="positive">Nodules</d> are observed in the <a>inner layer of the upper lobe of the right lung and just below the pleura</a>. There has been <c>no significant change</c> from <timex3 type="date">10 years ago</timex3>, so these are considered to be <d certainty="positive">benign lesions</d>.
<d certainty="positive">Bilateral lung metastases, subtracheal bifurcation, and bilateral mediastinal lymph node metastases</d> are <f>forming a bulky mass</f> with the <d certainty="positive">primary tumor</d>.
In addition, the <d certainty="positive">bilateral supraclavicular lymph nodes</d> are also <d certainty="positive">swollen</d>. This is also considered to be <d certainty="positive">metastasis</d>.
In addition, <d certainty="positive">nodules</d> were found on <a>both breasts, the liver, right adrenal gland, and lower abdomen</a>. All are considered to be <d certainty="positive">metastases</d>.
No <d certainty="negative">bone metastasis</d> is observed.
</article>
<article id="14" title="03">
A <f>28 mm</f> <d certainty="positive">nodular shadow</d> is seen in the <a>upper lobe S4 of the left lung</a>. A <d certainty="positive">ground-glass shadow</d> is seen on the <a>edge</a>, and an <d certainty="positive">air bronchogram</d> is present <a>inside</a>. Findings suspected of <d certainty="suspicious">lung adenocarcinoma</d> (<d>T1c</d>).
No <d certainty="negative">pathological lymphadenopathy</d> is seen in the <a>mediastinum, hilar, or axilla</a>.
There is no <d certainty="negative">cardiomegaly</d>.
No <d certainty="negative">pleural effusion</d> seen.
In addition, no <f>obvious</f> abnormality seen within the <a>observation range</a>.
</article>
<article id="15" title="01">
A <f>well-defined</f> <f>round</f> <d certainty="positive">ground-glass opacity (lepidic pattern)</d> of <f>approximately 18 mm</f>, mainly located on the <a>outside of the upper lobe of the left lung</a>is seen. The <d certainty="suspicious">enhancement</d> is <f>unknown</f>.
It is mainly a <f>lepidic growth pattern</f>, and it is not possible to point out <d certainty="negative">micro-infiltrating shadows</d>. <d certainty="suspicious">Primary lung cancer, adenocarcinoma in situ (AIS)</d> is suspected.
Compared to the <timex3 type="date">previous</timex3> image, <c>there is almost no change</c> in morphology, size, internal properties, etc. It seems to be a <f>slow-growing</f> <d certainty="suspicious">lesion</d>.
</article>
<article id="16" title="11">
A <f>large</f> <d certainty="positive">mass</d> is seen in the <a>right lung apex</a>. There are <d certainty="positive">tumors</d> in <a>Th2, Th3 vertebrae and right 2-3 ribs</a>.
<d certainty="positive">Infiltration and bone destruction</d> is evident. A <d certainty="suspicious">Pancoast tumor</d> (<d>T4</d>) is suspected. There are no <d certainty="negative">findings</d> to indicate <f>outright lymph node metastasis</f>.
There is no <d certainty="negative">cardiomegaly</d>.
No <d certainty="negative">pleural effusion</d> seen.
In addition, no <f>obvious</f> abnormality is identified <a>within the observation range</a>.
</article>
<article id="17" title="06">
A <d certainty="positive">mass lesion</d> is seen on the <a>central side of the lower right lobe</a>. <d certainty="suspicious">Primary lung cancer</d> is suspected. The<d certainty="negative">aeration</d> <a>in the periphery of the right lower lobe</a> <c>disappears</c>, forming an <d certainty="positive">atelectasis</d>. <f>Paraneoplastic</f> <d certainty="suspicious">pneumonia</d> is suspected. Due to the effects of <d certainty="positive">pneumonia and atelectasis</d>, it is <f>difficult to pinpoint the exact extent</f> of <d certainty="positive">tumour progression</d>.
<f>Numerous</f> <d certainty="positive">nodular shadows</d> are seen <a>from the right hilum to the superior mediastinum</a>. All of these point to suspicion of <d certainty="suspicious">lymph node metastases</d>.
</article>
<article id="18" title="13">
A <f>huge</f> <d certainty="positive">mass lesion</d> is observed in the <a>lower lobe of the left lung</a>. <f>Continuing</f> with the <d certainty="positive">tumour</d>, there is a <d certainty="positive">high-density area</d> <a>along the bronchial area</a>. The <a>left bronchus</a> is <f>surrounded</f> by a <d certainty="positive">tumour</d> and is considered <d certainty="positive">infiltrated</d>.
There is <d certainty="positive">lymphadenopathy</d> in the <a>ipsilateral hilum and mediastinum</a>, which is likely <d certainty="positive">metastasis</d>.
Based on the above, it is likely <d certainty="positive">left lung lower lobe lung cancer</d> (<d>T4N2</d>).
</article>
<article id="19" title="09">
<d certainty="suspicious">Lung cancer</d> suspected due to <f>irregular</f> <f>43mm diameter</f> <d certainty="positive">mass</d> in <a>right hilar region</a>. <d certainty="positive">Severe stenosis</d> in <a>lower right middle lobe bronchus</a> due to <d certainty="positive">infiltration</d>. <d certainty="positive">Ground glass shadow</d> indicating <d certainty="suspicious">pneumonia</d> spreading in <a>lower right lobe</a>. <a>Right upper lobe bronchus</a> also <d certainty="positive">stenotic</d>, indicating <d certainty="suspicious">invasion</d>.
<f>Irregular</f> <d certainty="positive">nodular shadow</d> in <a>right lower lobe</a>, which may indicate <d certainty="suspicious">intrapulmonary metastasis</d>. <d certainty="positive">Nodule shadows</d> also seen in <a>upper right lobe</a>. <timex3 type="date">Previously</timex3> seen on <t-test state="executed">CT</t-test> and is suspected to be a <d certainty="suspicious">benign nodule</d>.
Suspected <d certainty="suspicious">multiple lymph node metastasis</d> due to <d certainty="positive">enlarged lymph nodes</d> <f>scattered</f> in <a>mediastinum, left supraclavicular fossa, left gastric artery region, hilar region and paravalvular aorta</a>.
<d certainty="positive">Nodules</d> <f>scattered</f> on <a>both breasts</a>. Differential diagnosis of <d certainty="suspicious">metastasis and primary breast cancer</d>.
<f>Some</f> <d certainty="positive">hypovascular tumors</d> in <a>liver</a>. <d certainty="suspicious">Multiple liver metastases</d> suspected.
<d certainty="positive">Massive tumor</d> in <a>right adrenal gland</a>. Differential diagnosis of <d certainty="suspicious">metastases and adenoma</d>.
<d certainty="positive">Multiple nodules</d> <a>under skin</a>. <d certainty="suspicious">Skin metastasis</d> suspected.
<d certainty="positive">Left renal cyst</d> is seen.
No other abnormalities in <a>abdominal organs</a>.
<d certainty="suspicious">Uterine fibroids</d> are suspected.
No <d certainty="negative">thoracic fluid</d>.
</article>
<article id="20" title="03">
An <d certainty="positive">irregular shadow</d> with <f>a diameter of 28 mm</f> is seen in the <a>left lingular segment</a>. <d certainty="suspicious">Lung cancer</d> is suspected with <d certainty="positive">spicula and pleural incarceration</d>.
<d certainty="positive">Nodular shadows</d> are seen in the <a>lower right and upper left lobes</a>. First, <d certainty="suspicious">inflammatory changes</d> is suspected.
No <f>significant</f> <a>mediastinum or hilar</a> <d certainty="negative">lymphadenopathy</d> seen.
No <d certainty="negative">pleural effusion</d>.
</article>
<article id="21" title="11">
<d certainty="positive">Emphysematous changes</d> are <f>prominent</f> in <a>both lungs</a>, <a>mainly on the periphery</a>.
An <f>irregular</f> <d certainty="positive">intrapulmonary mass</d> of <f>○ × ○ cm in size</f> is found in the <a>right lung apex</a>, and <d certainty="suspicious">lung cancer</d> is suspected. The <d certainty="positive">mass</d> <d certainty="positive">invades</d> the <a>right 2nd and 3rd ribs and the Th2 and 3 vertebral bodies</a>, and at the <a>Th2 level</a>, it is suspected to <d certainty="suspicious">extend</d> <a>into the spinal canal</a> (<d>cT4</d>).
<f>Most</f> of the <d certainty="positive">nodules</d> in the <a>right middle lobe and the outer layers of the lower lobes of both lungs</a> have a <f>transbronchial</f> distribution, and <d certainty="suspicious">inflammatory nodules</d> are suspected. This is the patient's <timex3 type="date">first</timex3> <t-test state="executed">CT scan</t-test>, so please follow the <cc state="other">progress</cc> to see if this increases. There is nothing else to report in the <a>lungs or mediastinum</a>.
There is no <f>significant</f> <d certainty="negative">lymphadenopathy</d> (*Actually, it is stated that the <d certainty="positive">right hilar lymph node</d> is <d certainty="positive">enlarged</d> and <d certainty="suspicious">metastasis</d> is suspected).
There is no <d certainty="negative">pleural effusion</d>, but there is <f>mild</f> <d certainty="positive">left pleural thickening</d> with suspected <d certainty="suspicious">inflammatory changes</d>.
Impression (if any): Suspected <d certainty="suspicious">left upper lobe cancer</d> (<d>cT4N0MX</d>) *Without considering <d certainty="suspicious">brain metastasis</d> by <t-test state="executed">MRI</t-test>
</article>
<article id="22" title="02">
Comparison with <t-test state="executed">CT</t-test> from <timex3 type="date">3 years ago and 1 year ago</timex3>.
The <d certainty="positive">GGN</d> of the <a>lower lobe S6 of the left lung</a> has <c>increased</c> <f>from 9 mm to 12 mm in diameter</f>, and a <f>slight</f> <d certainty="positive">solid part</d> is observed <a>inside</a>.
From the progression, <d certainty="suspicious">neoplastic lesions such as adenocarcinoma in situ (AIS) and minimally invasive adenocarcinoma (MIA)</d> are suspected. A <t-test state="other">histological examination</t-test> should be carried out.
<f>Mild</f> <d certainty="positive">emphysematous changes</d> are observed <f>predominantly</f> in the <a>upper lung field</a>. <d certainty="positive">Nodules</d> <f>scattered</f> in the <a>upper lobe of the right lung and the lower lobes of both lungs</a> and <d certainty="positive">cord-like shadows</d> in the <a>bottom of the right lung</a> are suspected to be <d certainty="suspicious">old inflammatory changes</d>.
In addition, no <f>new</f> abnormalities are seen in the <a>lungs or mediastinum</a>.
No <f>significant</f> <d certainty="negative">lymphadenopathy or pleural effusion</d> is seen.
Impression (if any): <a>Left lower lobe</a> <d certainty="positive">GGN</d> (suspected <d certainty="suspicious">AIS, MIA</d>, etc.)
</article>
<article id="23" title="06">
A <d certainty="positive">soft tissue mass</d> is seen in the <a>right hilar region</a>, and <d certainty="suspicious">lung cancer</d> is suspected. This causes the <a>right middle lower lobe bronchus</a> to become <d certainty="positive">obstructed</d> and the <a>middle lower lobe</a> to become <d certainty="positive">atelectasis</d>. The <a>upper right lobe bronchus</a> may also be <d certainty="positive">narrowed</d> and visibly <d certainty="suspicious">infiltrated</d>. There seems to be no <d certainty="negative">progress</d> to the <a>tracheal bifurcation</a>.
In addition, no <f>obvious</f> <d certainty="negative">abnormal shadows</d> can be pointed out in the <a>aerated lung area</a>.
<d certainty="positive">Swelling lymph nodes</d> are <f>seen</f> in the <a>mediastinum and the left supraclavicular fossa</a>, and <d certainty="suspicious">metastasis</d> is suspected.
No <d certainty="negative">pleural effusion</d>.
</article>
<article id="24" title="12">
A <d certainty="positive">tumor</d> with <f>lobulated</f> <d certainty="positive">spicula</d> is observed in the <a>lower right lobe S6</a> and <d certainty="suspicious">primary lung cancer</d> is suspected. <f>Irregularly distributed</f> <d certainty="positive">multiple nodules</d> are observed in the <a>both lung fields</a>. Suspect <d certainty="suspicious">multiple secondary tumor nodules</d> in <a>both lung fields</a>. It seems to be equivalent to <d>T4</d> in the T classification.
<f>Significantly sized</f> <f>round</f> <d certainty="negative">supraclavicular fossa, mediastinum and hilar lymphadenopathy</d> cannot be identified.
<d certainty="negative">Pleural effusion</d> is not observed.
No <f>significant</f> abnormality can be identified in the <a>upper abdominal organs in the image shown</a>.
<f>Scattered</f> signs of <d certainty="positive">osteosclerotic changes</d> in the <a>thoracolumbar spine</a> can be observed. Suggested <d certainty="positive">bone metastasis</d>. It seems to be equivalent to <d>M1c</d> in M classification.
</article>
<article id="25" title="01">
<f>Mild</f> <d certainty="positive">emphysematous changes</d> can be seen in the <a>background of the lung field</a>.
A <d certainty="positive">bulla</d> is seen on the <a>apex of the lung</a>.
<d certainty="positive">Ground-glass-like shadows</d> with <f>clear boundaries</f> are observed in the <a>upper lobe of the left lung</a>, which are <f>slightly lobulated</f>.A <f>small</f> <d certainty="positive">high absorption area</d> is seen in the <a>centre</a>.The <f>length</f> of the <d certainty="positive">ground-glass shadow</d> is <f>18 mm</f>.<d certainty="suspicious">Well-differentiated adenocarcinoma</d> suspected, but a <t-test state="other">further CT scan</t-test> should be carried out <timex3 type="duration">in 1-2 months</timex3> to monitor the change in size. Assuming it is <d certainty="suspicious">lung cancer</d>, it may be <d>T1</d>.
The lesion is <a>detached from the pleura</a>.
Assuming it is <d certainty="suspicious">lung cancer</d>, <d certainty="negative">lesions</d> that are <f>positively suspected of lung metastasis</f> cannot be identified.
<d certainty="positive">Ground-glass shadowing</d> is <f>also seen</f> in the <a>lower lobe of the right lung</a>.These are <f>unclear</f> and <d certainty="suspicious">inflammatory changes</d> are suspected rather than <d certainty="suspicious">neoplastic lesions</d>. Please <t-test state="other">monitor their size</t-test> along with the above lesions.
On the <a>dorsal side of the lower lobes of both lungs</a>, there are <f>rectangular</f> <d certainty="positive">nodules</d> that appear to be <d certainty="suspicious">old inflammatory changes</d>.
A <d certainty="positive">cord-like shadow</d> is seen in the <a>lower lobe of the left lung</a>. This is considered to be an <d>old inflammatory change</d>.
No <d certainty="negative">pathological swelling</d> is seen in the <a>mediastinal or hilar lymph nodes</a>.
There is no <d certainty="negative">pleural effusion</d>.
There is a <d certainty="positive">hiatal hernia</d>.
<d certainty="negative">Nodules suspected of metastasis</d> to the <a>adrenal glands</a> cannot be pointed out.
Since there are no <t-key>soft tissue conditions</t-key>, it is difficult to evaluate the presence or absence of <d certainty="general">liver metastasis</d>.
</article>
<article id="26" title="02">
A <f>12 mm</f> <f>localised</f> <d certainty="positive">ground-glass shadow</d> is seen in the <a>lower lobe of the lung</a>. <f>Clear</f> <d certainty="negative">solid part</d> <a>inside</a> cannot be identified.
It is considered to be <d certainty="positive">lung adenocarcinoma</d> (equivalent to <d>Tis</d>).
</article>
<article id="27" title="03">
[<t-test state="executed">Routine chest CT</t-test>]
An <f>irregular</f> <d certainty="positive">solid nodule</d> <f>measuring approximately 24 mm in size</f> is seen in <a>S4 of the left lung area</a>, with <a>internal</a> <d certainty="positive">tracheal dilatation</d>. Possible <d certainty="suspicious">lung cancer</d> is suspected. Please consider <cc state="other">further examination</cc>.
A <d certainty="positive">ground-glass nodule</d> is also seen <a>just below the pleura of the upper lobe S1 + 2 of the left lung</a>. In addition to <d certainty="suspicious">inflammatory changes</d>, <d certainty="suspicious">dysplasia and early-stage adenocarcinoma</d> are also differentiated, and careful <cc state="other">follow-up</cc> is desired.
There are no <f>significant</f> <d certainty="negative">lymphadenopathy</d>.
No <d certainty="negative">tumours</d> are seen in the <a>liver, adrenal glands, or bone</a>.
<d certainty="positive">Emphysema</d> <f>seen</f> on the <a>background of the lung field</a>.
A <d certainty="positive">polymorphic small nodule</d> is seen in the <a>middle lobe S5 of the right lung</a>, but it seems to be a <d certainty="suspicious">benign lesion</d>.
There is<d certainty="positive"> a cord-like shadow</d> in the <a>lower lobe S6 of the right lung</a>, and <d certainty="suspicious">localised inflammation</d> is suspected.
<d certainty="positive">Arteriosclerosis</d> is observed. No abnormality is seen in the <a>upper abdominal organs in the imaging</a>.
</article>
<article id="28" title="12">
<f>Randomly distributed</f> <d certainty="positive">nodules</d> in <a>both lungs</a> suggesting <d certainty="suspicious">lung metastasis</d> (<d>cT4</d>). A <d certainty="positive">spiculated</d> <d certainty="positive">mass</d> of approximate <f>size of ○ × ○ cm</f> is observed in the <a>right lower lobe</a>, and is considered to be the <d certainty="positive">primary lesion</d>. There is <f>slight</f> <d certainty="positive">lymphatic tract development</d> in <a>both lung apexes</a>, but it is not enough to conclude that it is pulmonary <d certainty="suspicious">lymphangitic carcinomatosis</d>.
There is nothing else to report in the <a>mediastinum</a>.
Although <d certainty="positive">calcified lymph nodes</d> suspected to be caused by <d certainty="suspicious">previous tuberculosis</d> are found in the <a>right hilum and mediastinum</a>, no <f>significant</f> <d certainty="negative">enlargement</d> can be identified (<d>cN0</d>).
<d certainty="positive">Osteosclerosis</d> is observed in the <a>Th8-11 vertebral body</a>, and <d certainty="suspicious">bone metastasis</d> is suspected (unless following some kind of unless <timex3 type="med">post-radiation therapy</timex3>) (<d>cM1c</d>).
Impression (if any): Suspected <d certainty="suspicious">right lower lobe cancer</d> (<d>cT4N0M1c</d>): <d certainty="suspicious">Multiple lung metastases/thoracic spine metastases</d>
</article>
<article id="29" title="13">
<f>Mild</f> f>の<d certainty="positive">emphysematous changes</d> are seen <a>in both lungs</a>, and <d certainty="positive">bulla</d> are seen on the <a>lateral side of the upper lobe of the left lung</a>.
An <d certainty="positive">irregular mass</d> with <f>a diameter of 7.8 cm</f> and an <a>internal</a> <d certainty="positive">cavity</d> is seen in the <a>lower lobe of the left lung</a>, and <f>multiple</f> <d certainty="positive">lesions</d> suspected to be <d certainty="suspicious">accessory nodules</d> are seen in the <a>same lobe of the lung</a> (<d>cT4</d>). The <d certainty="positive">mass</d> is in <a>extensive contact with the pleura</a>, and the <a>extra-pleural fat layer</a> is <f>partially</f> <d certainty="positive">disrupted</d>, suggesting <d certainty="suspicious">parietal pleural infiltration</d>. <d certainty="suspicious">Infiltration</d> into the <a>ribs</a> is <f>unclear</f>. The <d certainty="positive">mass</d> is <a>partly in contact with the diaphragm</a>, but the <d certainty="suspicious">infiltration findings</d> are <f>unclear</f>.
<d certainty="positive">Swelling</d> of <a>ipsilateral</a> <d certainty="positive">mediastinal lymph nodes</d> such as the <a>left hilum, sub-tracheal bifurcation, and subaorta</a> is observed, and <d certainty="suspicious">metastasis</d> is suspected (<d>cN2</d>).
There are no other findings in the <a>lungs or mediastinum</a>. No <d certainty="negative">pleural effusion</d>.
<d certainty="positive">Liver cyst and mild splenomegaly</d> are observed.
There are no other findings in the <a>abdomen during imaging</a>.
Impression (if any): Suspected <d certainty="suspicious">lower left lobe lung cancer</d>(<d>cT4N2MX</d>)
</article>
<article id="30" title="13">
<d certainty="positive">Bulla</d> are <f>scattered</f> on <a>both sides of the lung apex</a>.
An <f>irregular</f> <d certainty="positive">mass</d> with a <f>length of 78 mm</f>, which is <f>mainly</f> located in the <a>lower right lobe S9</a>, is observed. It forms a <d certainty="positive">cavity</d> <a>inside</a>. <d certainty="suspicious">Primary lung cancer</d> is suspected. The <d certainty="positive">mass</d> is <a>laterally</a> in <a>extensive contact with the chest wall</a>, with <d certainty="positive">disruption</d> of the <a>extra-pleural fat layer</a>. <d certainty="positive">Infiltration of the chest wall</d> is suggested, and it seems to be equivalent to <d>T4</d> in the T classification.<f>Irregular</f> <d certainty="positive">nodules</d> are <f>scattered</f> in the <a>lower left lobe</a>,suspected to be <d certainty="suspicious">accessory tumour nodules</d>.
<a>Left hilar lymph node, #5, #7 mediastinal lymph nodes</a> are <d certainty="positive">swollen</d> and <d certainty="suspicious">metastasis</d> is suspected. It seems to be equivalent to <d>N2</d> in N classification.
No <d certainty="negative">pleural effusion</d> is observed.
No <f>significant</f> abnormality can be identified in the <a>upper abdominal organs in the imaging range</a>.
</article>
<article id="31" title="11">
An <f>obvious</f> <d certainty="positive">emphysemic change</d> has occurred in the <a>background of the pulmonary region</a>. It is suspected this is caused by <f>extended</f> <d certainty="suspicious">heavy use of cigarettes</d>, and given the background it is suspected that the risk for the development of <d certainty="suspicious">lung cancer</d> is high.
<a>Focusing on the right upper lobe</a>, we observed a <f>lobulated</f> <d certainty="positive">neoplastic lesion</d> with <f>clear boundaries</f> and <f>approximately x cm</f>. <d certainty="suspicious">Primary lung cancer</d> is suspected. It has <d certainty="positive">invaded</d> from the <a>apex of the lung through the mediastinum to the posterior chest wall</a>. There is also <d certainty="positive">osteolytic changes</d> to the <a>right ribs, right side of the vertebral bodies</a>, etc., and <d certainty="positive">invasion</d> into the <a>bones</a> is also observed.
We do not see any indications of <f>significant</f> <d certainty="negative">swelling</d> of the <a>lymph nodes</a>. We do not see any indications or <d certainty="negative">findings of suspected lymphatic metastases</d>.
There are no <d certainty="negative">findings of suspected distant metastases</d> that is visible <a>in the field of view</a>.
In addition, we do not observe any <f>obviously</f> <d certainty="negative">abnormal findings</d> that is identifiable <a>in the field of view</a>.
</article>
<article id="32" title="09">
A <d certainty="positive">tumor</d> with <f>a diameter of 43 mm</f> and an <f>unclear boundary</f> is found in the <a>right hilum</a>.
There appears to be no <f>apparent</f> <d certainty="negative">mediastinal invasion</d>.
The <a>right middle and lower lobe bronchi</a> are <d certainty="positive">highly stenotic</d> on the <a>central side</a>, but <a>peripheral</a> <d certainty="positive">aeration</d> is maintained.
<d certainty="positive">Irregular nodules</d> suspected to be <d certainty="suspicious">additional tumor nodules</d> are found in the <a>periphery</a> of the <a>lower lobe of the right lung</a>.
There is a <d certainty="positive">ground-glass opacity</d> in the <a>peripheral lower lobe of the right lung</a>, which is considered to be an <d certainty="positive">obstructive pneumonia caused by a mass or mucus plug</d>.
There are <d certainty="positive">nodules</d> in the <a>upper lobe of the right lung</a>, both <a>central and subpleural</a>, but these have been noted since <timex3 type="date">10 years ago</timex3>, so these are considered to be <d certainty="positive">benign lesions</d>.
The T factor is considered to be <d>T3</d>.
The <a>right hilar lymph node</a> is <f>lumped together</f> with the <d certainty="positive">tumour</d> and appears to <f>progressively</f> <d certainty="positive">enlarge</d>.
There are also <f>numerous</f> <d certainty="positive">pathologically enlarged lymph nodes</d> in <a>other mediastinal and bilateral supraclavicular fossa lymph node</a>.
The N factor is considered to be <d>N3</d>.
There is no <d certainty="negative">pleural effusion</d>.
<f>Multiple</f> <a>intrahepatic</a> <d certainty="positive">masses</d> are present. In the absence of a <t-test state="negated">simple CT</t-test>, it is not possible to determine the effect of contrast, but it is univocally considered a <d certainty="positive">metastasis</d>.
There is also a <d certainty="positive">mass</d> in the <a>right adrenal gland</a>. There is no <t-test state="negated">simple</t-test> information here either, it is difficult to distinguish, but it can be inferred that there is a high possibility of <d certainty="suspicious">metastasis</d>.
There is a <d certainty="positive">mass</d> on the <a>right side of the pelvis</a>. <d certainty="suspicious">Right ovarian metastasis</d> is suspected.
The presence of <f>numerous</f> <d certainty="positive">pathologically enlarged lymph nodes</d> in the <a>hilar region, around the celiac artery and in the para-aorta</a> is considered <d certainty="positive">metastatic</d>.
No other <d certainty="negative">metastases</d> in the <a>abdominal organs</a> can be detected.
There is no <d certainty="negative">evidence of ascites</d>.
<f>Multiple</f> <d certainty="positive">masses</d> in the <a>bilateral breast and in the adipose tissue of the abdominal and chest walls</a> and are also universally considered to have a high possibility of <d certainty="suspicious">metastases</d>.
The M factor is considered to be <d>M1c</d>.
</article>
<article id="33" title="13">
An <d certainty="positive">irregular mass</d> with a <f>major axis of 78 mm</f> is seen <a>under the pleura of the lower lobe of the left lung</a>. It is likely <d certainty="positive">lung cancer</d>.
The <d certainty="positive">fat layer between the mass and the pleura has disappeared</d>, indicating <d certainty="suspicious">pleural infiltration</d>.
<f>Many</f> <d certainty="positive">irregular nodules</d>, which may be <d certainty="positive">accessory tumour nodules</d>, are seen in the <a>lower lobe of the left lung</a>.
The T factor is considered to be <d>T4</d>.
<d certainty="negative">Nodules suspected of metastasis</d> to <a>other lobes</a> cannot be identified.
<d certainty="positive">Bulla</d> are seen on <a>both sides of the lung apex</a>.
<f>Multiple</f> <d certainty="positive">pathological swollen lymph nodes</d> are seen in the <a>left hilar region, under the tracheal bifurcation, and in the ipsilateral mediastinum</a>, and are considered to be <d certainty="positive">metastases</d>.
The N factor is considered to be <d>N2</d>.
There is no <d certainty="negative">pleural effusion</d>.
There is no <d certainty="negative">bone destruction strongly indicating bone metastasis or mass shadows</d> in the <a>imaging range</a>.
Other <d certainty="negative">distant metastases</d> cannot be identified.
The M factor is considered to be <d>M0</d>.
</article>
<article id="34" title="11">
A <f>huge</f> <d certainty="positive">mass lesion</d> is found in the <a>apex of the right lung</a>.
The <d certainty="positive">mass</d> has <d certainty="positive">invaded</d> the <a>right 1-3 ribs</a>, and there is considered to be <d certainty="positive">chest wall infiltration</d>.
There is also <d certainty="positive">infiltration</d> of the <a>Th2-3 vertebral body</a>.
<d certainty="positive">Multiple nodules</d> are found in the <a>lower lobes of both lungs</a>, which are considered to be <d certainty="positive">multiple intrapulmonary metastases</d>.
Based on the above, it is considered to be <d>cT4N0M1</d>.
</article>
<article id="35" title="01">
An <d certainty="positive">SSN</d> with <f>a diameter of 18 mm</f> is seen in the <a>upper left lobe</a>. It could be <d certainty="suspicious">AAH or AIS</d>.
<d certainty="positive">GGN</d> are also <f>scattered</f> in the <a>lower right lobe</a>. It may be an <d certainty="suspicious">inflammatory change</d>, but please monitor changes by <cc state="other">following up</cc>.
A <d certainty="positive">linear cord-like shadow</d> is seen in the <a>lower left lobe</a>, and <d certainty="suspicious">old inflammatory changes</d> are suspected.
No <f>significant</f> <a>mediastinum or hilar</a> <d certainty="positive">lymphadenopathy</d> seen.
No <d certainty="negative">pleural effusion</d>.
</article>
<article id="36" title="06">
<t-test state="executed">Contrast-enhanced CT shows</t-test> a <f>slightly darkly</f> stained <d certainty="positive">mass shadow</d> in the <a>hilar region of the lower lobe of the right lung</a>. Its <a>periphery</a> presents with <d certainty="positive">atelectasis</d>.
Suspect <d certainty="suspicious">hilar lung cancer</d> (<d>T2</d>).
<d certainty="positive">Enlarged lymph nodes</d> are seen in the <a>subcarinal lymph nodes, para-aortic lymph nodes, and supraclavicular lymph nodes</a>. It seems to be <d>N3</d>.
No <d certainty="negative">cardiomegaly</d> seen.
No <d certainty="negative">pleural effusion</d> seen.
In addition, no <f>obvious</f> abnormality seen <a>within the observation range</a>.
</article>
<article id="37" title="02">
A <f>relatively well-defined</f> <d certainty="positive">pure GGN</d> of <f>12 mm in size</f> is seen in the <a>lower right lobe S6</a>. <timex3 type="date">One year ago</timex3>, the <f>length was about 9 mm</f>, and there is an <c>increasing trend</c>. Although the <c>appearance</c> of a <f>clear</f> <d certainty="negative">solid core</d> cannot be seen, considering its progression, <d certainty="suspicious">AAH/AIS</d> may be possible, so please consider <cc state="other">further examinations</cc> and lab tests.
An <f>irregular</f> <d certainty="positive">ground-glass shadow</d> <c>appears</c> on the <a>dorsal side of the lower right lobe on the caudal side</a>. This may be an <d certainty="suspicious">inflammatory change</d>, but please <cc state="other">follow up</cc> as well.
In the <a>lower lobe of the left lung</a>, a <d certainty="positive">nodule that appears to be an old inflammatory change</d> is seen <a>just below the pleura</a>.
<f>Mild</f> <d certainty="positive">emphysematous changes</d> are seen in the <a>upper lung field</a>.
No other <f>coarse</f> <d certainty="negative">masses or infiltrative shadows</d> are seen in the <a>lung field</a>.
No <f>significant</f> <d certainty="negative">mediastinal lymphadenopathy or pleural effusion</d>.
</article>
<article id="38" title="11">
<d certainty="positive">Emphysematous changes</d> are seen on the <a>background of the lung field</a>.
Suspected <d certainty="suspicious">lung cancer</d> due to <f>large</f> <d certainty="positive">mass lesion</d> on <a>right lung apex</a>. Suspected <d certainty="suspicious">infiltration</d> due to <d certainty="positive">indication of damage</d> to <a>right 2nd and 3rd ribs and Th2 and 3 vertebrae</a>.
<f>Scattered</f> <d certainty="positive">small nodular shadows</d> in <a>both lung fields</a>. Consistent with <d certainty="suspicious">inflammation</d>. <d certainty="suspicious">Metastasis</d> cannot be ruled out. <cc state="other">Follow up</cc> check required to detect  changes.
No <f>significant</f> <a>mediastinum or hilar</a> <d certainty="negative">lymphadenopathy</d> seen.
No <d certainty="negative">pleural effusion</d>.
</article>
<article id="39" title="03">
The known <d certainty="positive">lung adenocarcinoma lesion</d> in <a>S3 of the left upper lung</a> is <f>2.8 cm in diameter</f>, and <f>some</f> <d certainty="positive">pleural infiltration images</d> are seen, but no <d certainty="negative">evidence of pleural infiltration</d> is observed (<d>cT1c</d>).
In addition, <d certainty="positive">nodular shadows</d> <a>continuous with the pleural surface</a> are also observed in <a>S1 + 2 in the upper left lung and S6 in the lower lobe of the right lung</a>, but <d certainty="suspicious">neoplastic lesions</d> cannot be ruled out here either, so <cc state="other">follow-up</cc> should be performed.
<f>Moderate</f> <d certainty="positive">emphysematous changes</d> are present in <a>both lungs</a>.
There are no other findings in the <a>lungs or mediastinum</a>.
No <f>significant</f> <d certainty="negative">lymphadenopathy or pleural effusion</d> (<d>cN0</d>).
<d certainty="positive">Calcification</d> of the <a>aortic wall</a> is observed.
There are no special findings in the <a>abdomen during imaging</a>.
Impression (if mentioned): <d certainty="positive">Upper left lobe lung cancer</d> (<d>cT1cN0MX</d>)
</article>
<article id="40" title="01">
The <f>lobulated part</f> with a <f>length of 18 mm</f> <a>in contact with the pleura</a> on the <a>outside of  the upper left lobe S1 + 2</a> has <d certainty="positive">part-solid GGN</d>.
The <d certainty="positive">solid part</d> is <f>() mm in diameter</f>, and distinguishes between <d certainty="suspicious">adenocarcinoma in situ (AIS), minimally invasive adenocarcinoma (MIA) and lepidic predominant adenocarcinoma (LPA)</d>. It seems to be equivalent to <d>T1mi</d> in T classification. <d certainty="positive">Nodules</d> are seen in the <a>bilateral lower lobe S6</a>, but morphologically <d certainty="suspicious">benign nodules such as old inflammatory nodules</d> are suspected.
A <d certainty="positive">cord-like shadow</d> is seen on the <a>bottom of the left lung</a>, suggesting an <d certainty="suspicious">inflammatory scar</d>.
It is not possible to point out <f>obvious</f> <d certainty="negative">intrapulmonary nodules that are suspicious of accessory tumour nodules</d>.
No <d certainty="negative">infiltration shadows in the lung field suspected of active pneumonia </d>.
</article>
<article id="41" title="12">
A <d certainty="positive">mass lesion</d> is found in the <a>lower lobe S6 of the right lung</a>.
<f>Multiple diffuse</f> <d certainty="positive">pulmonary nodules</d> observed in <a>both lungs</a>. These are considered <d certainty="positive">multiple intrapulmonary metastases</d>.
<f>Round</f> <d certainty="positive">lymph nodes</d> are observed in the <a>bilateral supraclavicular fossa</a>. Not a <f>significant</f> <d certainty="negative">swelling</d>, but suspected <d certainty="suspicious">metastasis</d>.
<d certainty="positive">Osteosclerosis</d> is observed in the <a>Th9-11 vertebral body</a>, which is considered <d certainty="positive">multiple bone metastases</d>.
Based on the above, it is considered to be <d>cT4N3M1c</d>.
</article>
<article id="42" title="06">
<f>Mild</f> <d certainty="positive">emphysematous changes</d> are seen in <a>both lungs</a>.
A <d certainty="positive">mass</d> that <f>fills</f> the <a>right hilum and the lower lobe of the right lung</a> with <f>little enhancement effect</f> is seen, and a <f>slightly </f> <d certainty="positive">enhanced part</d> is seen in the <a>hilar region</a>. Although it is <f>difficult to accurately evaluate the tumour diameter</f>, <d certainty="suspicious">hilar lung cancer</d> is suspected, and <d certainty="suspicious">mucous plugs</d> are suspected in the <a>peripheral</a> <d certainty="positive">poorly enhanced area</d>. The <a>right lower lobe bronchus</a> is <d certainty="positive">narrowed by the tumour</d>, and the <a>peripheral lower lobe</a> presents with <f>obstructive</f> <d certainty="positive">partial atelectasis</d> (<d>cT2</d>). The <a>upper and middle lobes of the right lung</a> are <d certainty="positive">slightly hyper-inflated</d>. The <a>right pulmonary arteriovenous</a> is <d certainty="positive">narrowed</d> <a>near the tumour</a>.
No other abnormalities such as <d certainty="negative">accessory nodules</d> can be seen in the <a>lung field</a>.
The <d certainty="positive">swollen lymph nodes</d> in the <a>mediastinum under the right hilum and tracheal bifurcation</a> are <f>clustered</f> with the <d certainty="positive">tumour</d>, and the <a>right main bronchus to intermediate bronchus and left main bronchus</a> are in <f>wide contact</f>. In addition, <d certainty="positive">swelling</d> of the the <a>superior mediastinal lymph nodes including the contralateral side</a> is seen, and <d certainty="positive">swelling of the left supraclavicular lymph nodes</d> is also seen (<d>cN3</d>).
No <d certainty="negative">pleural effusion</d>.
No <f>coarse</f> <d certainty="negative">bone lesions</d> are seen in the <a>imaging</a>.
Impression (if any): <d certainty="suspicious">Right hilar lung cancer</d> (<d>cT2N3MX</d>): <a>Peripheral</a> <d certainty="positive">obstructive atelectasis</d>
</article>
<article id="43" title="02">
A <f>12 mm diameter</f> <d certainty="positive">GGN</d> is seen in the <a>lower right lobe</a> and is visible with a <f>small</f> <d certainty="positive">solid part</d> <a>inside</a>. It has <c>increased slightly</c> compared to the <timex3 type="date">previous time</timex3>, and there is a possibility of <d certainty="suspicious">early lung cancer</d>.
<d certainty="positive">Linear cord-like shadows</d> are seen in <a>both lower lobes</a>, and <d certainty="suspicious">old inflammatory changes</d> are suspected.
No <f>significant</f> <a>mediastinum or hilar</a> <d certainty="negative">lymphadenopathy</d> seen.
No <d certainty="negative">pleural effusion</d>.
</article>
<article id="44" title="11">
A <d certainty="positive">lobulated tumor</d> that <a>strongly contacts the chest wall</a> is found in the <a>apex of the right lung</a>, and the <d certainty="suspicious">lung cancer</d> you indicated is suspected.
<d certainty="positive">Bone destruction</d> is observed in the <a>Th2,3 vertebral body and the right 2nd and 3rd ribs</a>, suggesting <d certainty="positive">direct infiltration</d> (<d>T4</d>).
Other <f>obvious</f> <d certainty="negative">abnormal shadows</d> cannot be identified in the <a>lung field</a>.
<d certainty="positive">Emphysematous changes</d> <f>predominantly</f> in the <a>upper lung field</a> are observed.
<f>Significant</f> <d certainty="negative">mediastinal lymphadenopathy</d> cannot be pointed out.
No <f>significant</f> <d certainty="negative">pleural effusion</d> is observed.
</article>
<article id="45" title="01">
Comparison with <t-test state="executed">CT</t-test> from <timex3 type="date">1 year ago</timex3>.
In the <a>left lung upper section S1 + 2</a>, the <d>part solid GGN</d> with a <f>large diameter of 18 mm</f> has a <c>smaller</c> <a>internal</a> <d certainty="positive">solid part</d> than the <timex3 type="date">previous time</timex3>, but the size of the <d certainty="positive">ground-glass shadow</d> has <c>not shrunk</c> compared to the <timex3 type="date">previous time</timex3>,
and is accompanied by a <f>slight</f> <d certainty="positive">pleural invagination</d>. <d certainty="suspicious">Neoplastic lesions such as adenocarcinoma in situ (AIS) and minimally invasive adenocarcinoma (MIA)</d> should be considered.
<d certainty="positive">Bulla</d> are seen at the <a>apex of both lungs</a>, <d certainty="positive">nodules</d> are seen in the <a>upper and middle lobes of the right lung and the lower lobe of the left lung</a>, and <d certainty="positive">linear cord-like shadows</d> are seen <f>predominantly</f> on the <a>left side</a> of the <a>lower lobes of both lungs</a>, suspected of <d certainty="suspicious">old inflammatory change</d>.
<d certainty="positive">Hiatal hernia</d> is seen.
<d certainty="positive">Small lymph nodes</d> are <f>scattered</f> in the <a>mediastinum, such as near the right trachea</a>, but there is no <f>significant</f> <d certainty="negative">swelling</d>.
No <d certainty="negative">pleural effusion</d> is seen.
<d certainty="positive">Splenomegaly</d> is seen.
There are no other findings in the <a>abdomen during imaging</a>.
Impression (if any): <a>Left lung upper section</a> <d certainty="positive">GGN</d> (suspected <d certainty="suspicious">AIS, MIA</d>, etc.)
<d certainty="positive">Oesophageal hiatus hernia</d>
</article>
<article id="46" title="01">
A <f>well-defined</f> <d certainty="positive">GGN</d> with <f>a diameter of 18 mm</f> is seen in the <a>upper lobe S1 + 2 of the left lung</a>. The <a>marginal border</a> is <f>clear</f> and is accompanied by a <d certainty="positive">pleural invagination</d>. A <d certainty="suspicious">solid core</d> is suspected in the <a>centre</a>. Since it is possible <d certainty="suspicious">AAH/AIS</d>, please consider <cc state="other">further examination</cc> and <t-test state="other">lab tests</t-test>.
<d certainty="positive">Ground-glass shadows</d> with <f>unclear boundaries</f> can be seen in the <a>lower lobe of the right lung</a>. This may be an <d certainty="suspicious">inflammatory change</d>, but please <cc state="other">follow up</cc> as well.
In the <a>lower lobe of the left lung</a>, a <f>polygonal</f> <d certainty="positive">nodule</d> that seems to be an <d certainty="suspicious">old inflammatory change</d> is seen <a>just below the pleura</a>.
A <d certainty="positive">cord-like shadow</d> that appears to be an <d certainty="suspicious">inflammatory scar</d> is seen in the <a>middle lobe lingular segment and the bottom of the left lung</a>.
<d certainty="positive">Pleural thickening</d>, which appears to be an <d certainty="suspicious">old inflammatory change</d>, is observed in the <a>apex of the lung</a>.
<f>Mild</f> <d certainty="positive">emphysematous changes</d> are seen in the <a>upper lung field</a>.
No other <f>coarse</f> <d certainty="negative">masses or infiltrative shadows</d> are seen in the <a>lung field</a>.
No <f>significant</f> <d certainty="negative">mediastinal lymphadenopathy or pleural effusion</d>.
</article>
<article id="47" title="06">
A <d certainty="positive">mass lesion</d> is seen in the <a>right hilar region</a>, accompanied by <d certainty="positive">stenosis</d> of the <a>intermediate bronchial trunk</a>. It seems to be the <d certainty="positive">known lung cancer</d>. This causes a <d certainty="positive">decrease in volume and atelectasis</d> in the <a>lower right lobe</a>, making it difficult to assess tumour diameter.
The <a>right hilar lymph nodes</a> may be <d certainty="suspicious">swollen</d> <f>together</f> with the <d certainty="positive">tumour</d>. <d certainty="positive">Many swollen</d> <a>sub-tracheal, superior mediastinum, and left supraclavicular lymph nodes</a> also suggest <d certainty="positive">metastasis</d> (<d>N3</d>).
Other <f>obvious</f> <d certainty="negative">abnormal shadows</d> cannot be identified in the <a>lung field</a>.
No <f>significant</f> <d certainty="negative">pleural effusion</d> is observed.
No <f>obvious</f> <d certainty="negative">metastasis</d> can be identified in the <a>liver or adrenal gland in the imaging range</a>.
The <a>liver</a> is <d certainty="positive">swollen in the left lobe</d> and has a <f>blunt margin</f>. Possible <d certainty="suspicious">chronic liver damage</d>.
</article>
<article id="48" title="03">
An <d certainty="positive">irregular shadow</d> with a <f>large diameter of 28 mm</f> and a <f>clear boundary</f> is observed in <a>S4 of the left lingular segment</a>. The <a>margin</a> is accompanied by <d certainty="positive">spicula and pleural invagination</d>, which is consistent with <d>T1b</d> <d certainty="positive">lung cancer</d>. <d certainty="negative">Findings</d> <f>strongly suspected of pleural infiltration</f> cannot be identified.
<d certainty="positive">Irregular nodules</d> are observed in the <a>lower lobe of the right lung</a>. It may be an <d certainty="suspicious">inflammatory change</d>, but please <cc state="other">follow up</cc> as well.
<d certainty="positive">Pleural thickening, which appears to be an old inflammatory change</d>, is observed in the <a>apex of the lung</a>.
No other <f>coarse</f> <d certainty="negative">masses or infiltrative shadows</d> are seen in the <a>lung field</a>.
No <f>significant</f>  <d certainty="negative">mediastinal lymphadenopathy or pleural effusion</d>.
</article>
<article id="49" title="11">
A <f>large</f> <d certainty="positive">mass</d> is seen in the <a>right lung apex</a>. It is likely <d certainty="positive">lung cancer</d>.<f></f>
There is <d certainty="positive">destruction</d> of the <a>right second and third ribs and the second and third thoracic vertebrae</a> where the <d certainty="positive">mass</d> is in <f>contact</f>, suggesting <d certainty="positive">invasion</d>.
The T factor is considered to be <d>T4</d>.
The <a>background of the lung fields</a> show <f>moderate to severe</f> <d certainty="positive">emphysematous changes</d>.
There are <d certainty="positive">small nodules</d> <f>scattered</f> in the <a>middle lobe of the right lung and in the periphery of the lower lobes of both lungs</a>. They all exhibit <f>rectangular shapes</f> and are suspected to be <d certainty="suspicious">obsolete inflammatory changes</d> rather than <d certainty="suspicious">metastases</d>.
There are no <d certainty="negative">pathologically enlarged lymph nodes</d> in the <a>hilum, mediastinum or supraclavicular fossa</a>.
The N factor is considered to be <d>N0</d>.
There is no <d certainty="negative">pleural effusion</d>.
No <f>obvious</f> <d certainty="negative">distant metastases</d> can be noted in the <a>imaging area</a>.
</article>
<article id="50" title="12">
There are <f>mottled</f> <d certainty="positive">infiltration shadows and ground glass shadows</d> in the <a>bilateral lung fields</a>. A <d certainty="positive">nodular shadow</d> <f>slightly larger than the peripheral area</f> is found in <a>S10 in the lower lobe of the right lung</a>. We suspect <d certainty="suspicious">mucinous adenocarcinoma</d> and <f>multiple</f> <d certainty="suspicious">intrapulmonary metastasis</d>. It seems to be <d>T4</d>.
No <d certainty="negative">pathological lymphadenopathy</d> is seen in the <a>mediastinum, hilar, or axilla</a>.
No <d certainty="negative">cardiomegaly</d> seen.
No <d certainty="negative">pleural effusion</d> seen.
<t-test state="executed">Bone window imaging</t-test> shows <d certainty="positive">diffuse osteosclerosis</d> in the <a>Th8-11 vertebrae</a>. We suspect <d certainty="suspicious">bone metastasis</d>.
In addition, no <f>obvious</f> abnormality is identified <a>within the observation range</a>.
</article>
<article id="51" title="01">
<d certainty="positive">Bulla</d> are seen on <a>both sides of the lung apex</a>.
<f>18 × 15 mm</f> <d certainty="positive">part-solid GGN</d> is seen in the <a>upper lobe S1 + 2 of the left lung</a>. The <f>size of the solid part is unknown</f>, but as a whole, there is <c>no size change</c> from the <timex3 type="date">previous</timex3> image, and there is a suspicion of <d certainty="suspicious">lung adenocarcinoma</d>.
No <d certainty="negative">pathological lymphadenopathy</d> is seen in the <a>mediastinum, hilar, or axilla</a>.
There is no <d certainty="negative">cardiomegaly</d>.
No <d certainty="negative">pleural effusion</d> seen.
In addition, no <f>obvious</f> abnormality can be pointed out in the <a>observation range</a>.
</article>
<article id="52" title="02">
A <d certainty="positive">ground-glass nodule</d> with a <f>relatively clear border</f> is seen in the <a>lower lobe S6 of the right lung</a>. The <f>major axis diameter is 12 mm</f>. Since the <f>major axis was 9 mm</f> the <timex3 type="date">last time</timex3>, it has <c>increased slightly</c> over the course of <timex3 type="duration">one year</timex3>. It <f>contains</f> a <d certainty="positive">high concentration part</d>, there is a higher possibility of <d certainty="suspicious">well-differentiated adenocarcinoma</d> than <d certainty="suspicious">inflammatory changes</d>. Assuming it is <d certainty="suspicious">lung cancer</d>, the T factor is considered to be <d>T1a</d>.
The lesion is <a>detached from the pleura</a>.
<d certainty="negative">Lesions suspected of lung metastasis</d> cannot be identified.
On the <a>dorsal side of the lower lobes of both lungs</a>, <d certainty="positive">cord-like shadows that appear to be old inflammatory changes</d> are seen.
No <d certainty="negative">pathological swelling</d> is seen in the <a>mediastinal or hilar lymph nodes</a>. The N factor is considered to be <d>N0</d>.
There is no <d certainty="negative">pleural effusion</d>.
The M factor cannot be determined and is <d certainty="positive">MX</d>.
</article>
<article id="53" title="06">
There is a <d certainty="positive">mass lesion</d> with an <f>unclear border</f> in the <a>lower lobe of the right lung</a>. It appears to be the <d certainty="positive">lung cancer</d> you observed. The <a>middle trunk</a> <f>passes through</f> the <a>tumour</a> and is <d certainty="positive">obstructed</d>. It is <d certainty="positive">infiltrated</d>. <d certainty="positive">Atelectasis</d> is present in the <a>middle and lower lobes of the right lung</a>.
<d certainty="positive">#6, #2L, #7, #3p, #4L, #5 lymphadenopathy</d> is observed and considered <d certainty="positive">metastatic lymph nodes</d>. The <d certainty="positive">tumour and #7 lymph nodes</d> are a <f>mass</f>.
There is <d certainty="positive">bronchial infiltration</d>, equivalent to <d>T2</d>, and <d certainty="positive">contralateral mediastinal lymph node metastasis</d>, which is considered to be equivalent to <d>N3</d>.
</article>
<article id="54" title="02">
A <d certainty="positive">ground-glass shadow</d> with a <f>long diameter of 12 mm</f> is observed on the <a>lower right lobe S6</a>. A <d certainty="positive">solid part</d> of <f>about () mm</f> is seen <a>inside</a>, and it seems to be a lesion corresponding to the <d certainty="suspicious">part-solid GGN</d>. It may be <d certainty="suspicious">adenocarcinoma in situ (AIS), minimally invasive adenocarcinoma (MIA) and lepidic predominant adenocarcinoma (LPA)</d>. It seems to be equivalent to <d>T1mi</d> in T classification. It is not possible to point out <d certainty="negative">intrapulmonary nodules</d> that are <f>obviously suspected of accessory tumour nodules</f>.
</article>
<article id="55" title="11">
There is a <d certainty="positive">mass</d> in the <a>apex of the right lung</a>. This is thought to be the known <d certainty="positive">lung cancer</d>.
<d certainty="positive">Damage</d> to <a>Th2 vertebra, Th2 right spinous process, Th3 vertebra, and right 2nd to 3rd ribs</a>. There appears to be <d certainty="positive">infiltration</d> into the <a>chest wall and vertebrae</a>.
It is <a>also close to the right subclavian artery</a>. It is not <f>clear</f> if there is <d certainty="negative">infiltration</d> into the <a>large artery</a>.
<d certainty="negative">Regional lymph node tumors</d> and <d certainty="negative">distant metastasis</d> are not <f>clear</f> from <a>imaging</a>.
<d certainty="positive">Emphysema</d> <f>seen</f> on the <a>background of the lung field</a>.
</article>
<article id="56" title="12">
<f>Irregular</f> <d certainty="positive">mass</d> in <a>lower right lobe</a> with <d certainty="positive">spicula and pleural intrusion</d>. <d certainty="suspicious">Lung cancer</d> is suspected.
<f>Diffuse</f> <d certainty="positive">nodular shadows</d> in <a>both lung fields</a>. Potential for <d certainty="suspicious">multiple lung metastases</d>. <d certainty="suspicious">Miliary tuberculosis</d> differential diagnosis. Check medical history.
No <f>significant</f> <a>mediastinum or hilar</a> <d certainty="negative">lymphadenopathy</d> seen.
No <d certainty="negative">pleural effusion</d>.
<a>Liver</a> shows <f>mildly irregular contour</f> and a <f>blunt edge</f>, indicating <d certainty="positive">chronic liver damage</d>.
<d certainty="positive">Sclerotic images</d> on <a>vertebrae and pelvic bone</a>. Potential for <d certainty="suspicious">multiple bone metastases</d>.
</article>
<article id="57" title="02">
[<t-test state="executed">Routine chest CT</t-test>]
Comparison with the previous <t-test state="executed">CT</t-test> <timex3 type="date">one year ago</timex3> was done.
A <f>12 mm large</f> <d certainty="positive">pure GGN</d> was seen in the <a>lower lobe of the right lung</a>, which was <f>about 3 mm</f> <c>larger</c> than <timex3 type="date">one year ago</timex3>. The <d certainty="positive">solid component</d> is <f>not clear</f>.
<d certainty="suspicious">Atypical adenomatous hyperplasia or minimally invasive adenocarcinoma</d> are also likely to be differentiated, and careful <t-test state="other">follow-up</t-test> is desired.
Although the image was taken only for <a>lung field</a> conditions, no <d certainty="negative">significant lymph node tumour</d> was observed within the imaging range.
No <f>obvious</f> <d certainty="negative">tumours</d> are found in the <a>liver, adrenal glands, or bones</a>.
</article>
<article id="58" title="13">
<d certainty="positive">Emphysematous changes</d> are seen on the <a>background of the lung field</a>.
A <d certainty="positive">mass lesion</d> with a <f>diameter of 78 mm</f> was seen in the <a>periphery of the lower left lobe</a>, accompanied by a <d certainty="positive">cavity</d>. <d certainty="suspicious">Lung cancer</d> is suspected. It is in <a>wide contact with the pleura</a> and may <d certainty="suspicious">infiltrate</d>. <f>Scattered</f> <d certainty="positive">nodular shadows</d> are also seen on the <a>central side</a>, <d certainty="positive">soft tissue shadows</d> <a>around the bronchi</a>, and the <a>bronchi</a> were <d certainty="positive">narrowed</d>. <d certainty="suspicious">Lung cancer lesions</d> are also suspected here.
<d certainty="positive">Swelling lymph nodes</d> are seen in the <a>left hilum and mediastinum</a>, and <d certainty="suspicious">metastasis</d> is suspected. There seems to be no <d certainty="negative">metastasis</d> to the <a>contralateral mediastinum</a>.
No <d certainty="negative">pleural effusion</d>.
</article>
<article id="59" title="03">
A <f>relatively well-defined</f> <f>dark</f> <d certainty="positive">ground glass nodule</d> is found in the <a>left lung tongue area</a>. It is likely <d certainty="positive">lung cancer</d>.
The <f>major axis diameter is 28 mm</f>. The T factor is considered to be <d>T1</d>.
The lesion is <a>detached from the pleura</a>.
<f>Small</f> <d certainty="positive">ground-glass shadows</d> are seen in the <a>lower lobe S6 of the right lung and the apex of the left lung</a>. There is a possibility that it can be <d certainty="suspicious">lung cancer</d> or <d certainty="suspicious">inflammatory changes</d>. Please <cc state="other">monitor their size</cc>.
<d certainty="negative">Lesions suspected of lung metastasis</d> cannot be identified.
No <d certainty="negative">pathological swelling</d> is seen in the <a>mediastinal or hilar lymph nodes</a>. The N factor is considered to be <d>N0</d>.
There is no <d certainty="negative">pleural effusion</d>.
There are no <d certainty="negative">bone destructions or mass lesions</d> that are <f>strongly suspected of bone metastasis</f>.
Other M factors cannot be determined and are <d>MX</d>.
</article>
<article id="60" title="01">
[<t-test state="executed">Routine chest CT</t-test>]
Comparison with the <timex3 type="date">previous</timex3> <t-test state="executed">CT</t-test> <timex3 type="date">one year ago</timex3> was done.
<a>Upper lobe S1 + 2 of the left lung</a> has a large <d certainty="positive">ground-glass nodule</d> with a <f>length of 18 mm</f>, accompanied by <d certainty="positive">solid components and tracheal dilatation</d>
. Although it is <c>not significantly different</c> from the <timex3 type="date">previous time</timex3>, <d certainty="suspicious">dysplasia and early lung adenocarcinoma</d> are still suspected, and careful <cc state="other">follow-up</cc> is desired.
<d certainty="positive">Emphysematous changes</d> are observed in <a>both lung apex</a>.
Only the <a>lung field</a> conditions were taken, but the <d certainty="negative">size of the lymph node tumour</d> is <f>not clear</f>. No <d certainty="negative">pleural effusion</d>.
</article>
<article id="61" title="13">
There is a <f>78 mm long</f> <d certainty="positive">mass</d> in the <a>lower lobe of the left lung</a>, which is considered to be the known <d certainty="positive">lung cancer</d>.
It is in <a>wide contact with the chest wall</a>, with <f>loss</f> of <a>adipose tissue on the chest wall</a> also seen. It may have <d certainty="suspicious">infiltrated</d> the <a>chest wall</a>.
<f>Multiple</f> <d certainty="positive">nodules</d> that appear to be <d certainty="suspicious">satellite lesions</d> on the <a>central side of the lower lobe of the left lung</a> are seen.
The <d certainty="positive">left hilar, sub-tracheal bifurcation, and lower left paratracheal lymph node</d> are <d certainty="positive">swollen</d> and are considered to be <d certainty="positive">lymph node metastasis</d>.
No <d certainty="negative">metastasis</d> was seen in the <a>liver or bone</a> <a>during imaging</a>. The <a>adrenal glands</a> are out of the imaging range.
</article>
<article id="62" title="11">
<d certainty="positive">Chronic emphysema</d> is observed in the background of the <a>lung field</a>.
A <f>lobular</f> <d certainty="positive">mass</d> is observed in the <a>apex of the right lung</a>. <d certainty="positive">Decalcification</d> in the <a>right 2nd/3rd thoracic vertebrae and right 2nd/3rd rib</a> observed, due to <a>contact with the right lung pulmonary apex region</a>. <d certainty="suspicious">Lung cancer permeation into the thoracic spine and ribs</d> is suspected. At the <a>2nd thoracic vertebrae level</a>, <d certainty="suspicious">tumor progression</d> <a>into the spinal canal</a> is suspected. <f>Numerous</f> <d certainty="positive">nodules</d> in <a>both lung fields</a> suspected to be <d certainty="suspicious">secondary tumor nodules</d> are observed. It seems to be equivalent to <d>T4</d> in the T classification.
<f>Significantly sized</f> <f>round</f> <d certainty="negative">supraclavicular fossa, mediastinum and hilar lymphadenopathy</d> cannot be identified.
<d certainty="negative">Pleural effusion</d> is not observed.
No <f>significant</f> abnormality can be identified in the <a>upper abdominal organs in the imaging range</a>.
</article>
<article id="63" title="09">
<a>Bilateral hilar and mediastinal</a> <d certainty="positive">lymph node enlargement</d> are observed and <d certainty="positive">mediastinal lymphadenopathy</d> <a>under the tracheal bifurcation</a> <f>fused with</f> a <d certainty="positive">mass</d> of <f>4.3 cm in size</f> were observed in the <a>right hilum</a>,corresponding to <d certainty="positive">small cell lung cancer metastases</d>. The <a>lower lobe bronchus</a> is <d certainty="positive">narrowed</d> by a <d certainty="positive">right hilar mass</d>, and <d certainty="positive">aspiration pneumonia</d> is observed on the <a>dorsal side of the right lower lobe</a>. There are also findings on the <a>ventral side</a> <d certainty="suspicious">that are suspected to be accessory nodules</d> <a>within the same lobe</a> (<d>cT3N3</d>).
There is nothing else to report in the <a>lungs or mediastinum</a>. No <d certainty="negative">pleural effusion</d> is observed.
<a>Lymph nodes around the hilum and celiac artery</a> are also <d certainty="positive">enlarged</d>, and <d certainty="suspicious">metastasis</d> is suspected. In addition, there are <f>multiple</f> <d certainty="positive">masses</d> suspected to be <d certainty="suspicious">metastasis</d> in the <a>right anterior chest, bilateral mammary glands, subcutaneous left back, liver and right adrenal gland</a> (<d>M1c</d>).
There is a <d certainty="positive">mass</d> of <f>○ × ○ × ○ cm in size</f> on the <a>right side of the pelvis</a>, and a <d certainty="suspicious">right adnexal mass or subserosal fibroid</d> is suspected. The <a>left appendage</a> appears to have <d certainty="suspicious">mild swelling</d>, but <f>it does not appear to be pathological</f>.
There is nothing else to report in the <a>abdomen</a>. <d certainty="negative">Ascites</d> is not confirmed.
Impression (if any): Suspected <d certainty="suspicious">right hilar small cell lung cancer</d> (<d>cT3N3M1c</d>)
</article>
<article id="64" title="02">
A <d certainty="positive">ground-glass nodule</d> of <f>approximately 12 mm</f> with an <f>unclear border</f> is seen in the <a>lower lobe S6 of the right lung</a>. Compared to the image <timex3 type="date">one year ago</timex3>, it has <c>clearly increased</c> <f>from approximately 9 mm to approximately 12 mm</f>. <d certainty="negative">Microinvasion</d> is <f>not clear</f>, but <d certainty="suspicious">minimally invasive adenocarcinoma (MIA)</d> is suspected.
</article>
<article id="65" title="06">
<d certainty="positive">Atelectasis</d> is seen in the <a>lower right lobe</a>. The <a>right lower lobe bronchus</a> is <d certainty="positive">occluded</d>, and a <d certainty="positive">mass</d> suspected to be <d certainty="suspicious">lung cancer</d> is seen in the <a>proximal part of the lower lobe bronchus</a>, which seems to be a <f>mass</f> with <d certainty="positive">enlarged mediastinal lymph nodes</d> <a>around the bronchus</a>. It is <f>difficult to determine</f> the <a>boundary</a> between <d certainty="positive">atelectasis</d> and the <d certainty="positive">tumour</d>, and accurate <d certainty="positive">tumour</d> <f>size cannot be evaluated</f>. No findings suggestive of <d certainty="negative">mediastinal infiltration</d>. No <d certainty="negative">lesions suspected to be accessory tumour nodules</d> can be noted in the <a>lung field</a>. It seems to be equivalent to <d>T2</d> in T classification.
<a>#1L, #2R, #2L, #4R, #4L, #5, #6, #7 lymph nodes</a> are <d certainty="positive">swollen</d> in a <f>round shape</f> and <d certainty="suspicious">metastasis</d> is suspected. It seems to be equivalent to <d>N3</d> in N classification.
No <d certainty="negative">pleural effusion</d> is observed.
No <f>significant</f> abnormality can be identified in the <a>upper abdominal organs in the imaging range</a>.
</article>
<article id="66" title="13">
A <f>78 mm</f> <d certainty="positive">mass</d> is seen in the <a>lower lobe S9 of the left lung</a>. The <a>edge</a> has <d certainty="positive">notches</d> and the <a>inside</a> has a <d certainty="positive">cavity</d>. The <a>inner wall of the cavity</a> is <f>slightly irregular</f>. There are <f>several</f> <f>consecutive</f> <f>irregular</f> <d certainty="positive">nodules</d> in the <a>lobe of the lung</a>. Suspect <d certainty="suspicious">peripheral lung cancer</d> with <d certainty="positive">cavity formation</d>. It is in <a>wide contact with the chest wall</a>, and the <a>chest wall adipose tissue</a> has <f>disappeared</f>. It seems to be <d>T4</d>.
The <d certainty="positive">left hilar lymph node and subcarinal lymph node</d> are <d certainty="positive">swollen</d> and indicate <d certainty="suspicious">lymph node metastasis</d>.
No <d certainty="negative">cardiomegaly</d> seen.
No <d certainty="negative">pleural effusion</d> seen.
In addition, no <f>obvious</f> abnormality seen <a>within the observation range</a>.
</article>
<article id="67" title="01">
A <d certainty="positive">localised ground-glass shadow</d> with an <f>unclear border</f> is seen in the <a>upper lobe of the left lung</a>. Confirming the <d certainty="positive">solid part</d> <a>inside</a>, it may be a <d>part-solid GGN</d>. The image indicates <d certainty="suspicious">lung cancer</d>.
<f>Partial</f> <d certainty="positive">pleural infiltration</d> is observed, but no <f>obvious</f> <d certainty="negative">pleural infiltration</d> can be identified.
The <d certainty="positive">full part</d> is <f>1 cm or less</f>, which is considered to be equivalent to <d>T1a</d>.
</article>
<article id="68" title="09">
There is an <d certainty="positive">obstruction</d> in the <a>middle and lower lobe bronchus of the right lung</a>, and there is a <f>43mm</f> <d certainty="positive">tumor</d> in the <a>right hilum</a> that is a <f>single mass</f> with the <d certainty="positive">lymph nodes</d>. <d certainty="suspicious">Hilar lung cancer</d> is suspected. There are <f>two</f> <f>oval</f> <f>irregular</f> <d certainty="positive">masses</d> on the <a>peripheral side</a>. <d certainty="positive">Intrapulmonary metastasis</d> is found. The <a>right lower lobe of the lung</a> has a frosted <d certainty="positive">glass shadow</d>, which is an <f>associated</f> <d certainty="positive">image of pneumonia</d>.
There is also a <d certainty="positive">nodular shadow</d> in the <a>upper lobe of the right lung</a>. This was also found in the <timex3 type="date">previous</timex3> <t-test state="executed">CT scan</t-test>, so there is <c>no significant change</c> compared to the <timex3 type="date">previous</timex3> scan. <d certainty="suspicious">Benign nodules</d> are suspected.
The <a>peribronchial lymph nodes, paraaortic lymph nodes, and left supraclavicular lymph nodes</a> are <d certainty="positive">swollen</d>, and we suspect <d certainty="suspicious">lymph node metastasis</d>. It seems to be <d>N3</d>.
<f>One</f> <d certainty="positive">nodule</d> is found in the <a>right breast</a> and <f>four</f> <d certainty="positive">nodules</d> in the <a>left breast</a>. We suspect <d certainty="suspicious">metastasis in the breast</d>.
<f>Many</f> <f>weak-stained</f> <d certainty="positive">nodules</d> are found in the <a>liver</a>. We suspect <d certainty="suspicious">multiple liver metastases</d>.
There are <d certainty="positive">nodules</d> on the <a>right adrenal gland</a>, and we suspect <d certainty="suspicious">adrenal metastasis</d>.
We did not find any <f>significant</f> observations regarding the <a>pancreas, spleen, or kidneys</a>.
There are also <d certainty="positive">nodules</d> beneath the skin in the <a>right upper abdomen</a>. We suspect <d certainty="suspicious">skin metastasis</d>.
In addition, no <f>obvious</f> abnormality is identified <a>within the observation range</a>.
</article>
<article id="69" title="02">
<d certainty="positive">Part-solid GGN</d> is seen in the <a>lower lobe S6 of the left lung</a>. Compared to the <timex3 type="date">previous</timex3> <t-test state="executed">CT</t-test>, the size has <c>increased</c> <f>from 9 mm to 12 mm</f>. Suspect <d certainty="suspicious">lung adenocarcinoma</d> (<d>T1</d>).
In addition, no <f>obvious</f> <d certainty="negative">nodular shadow</d> can be seen in the <a>lung field</a>.
No <d certainty="negative">pathological lymphadenopathy</d> is seen in the <a>mediastinum, hilar, axilla</a>, etc.
There is no <d certainty="negative">cardiomegaly</d>.
There is no <d certainty="negative">pleural effusion</d>.
No other <f>obvious</f> abnormalities are observed.
</article>
<article id="70" title="09">
A <d certainty="positive">right hilar mass</d> with <f>long diameter of 43 mm</f> is observed.
<d certainty="positive">Irregular nodules</d> are observed in the <a>lower right lobe</a>. <d certainty="negative">This lesion</d> could not be detected by <t-test state="executed">CT</t-test> scan from <timex3 type="date">10 years ago</timex3>, suspect <d certainty="suspicious">secondary tumor nodule</d>.  A <f>smooth peripheral</f> <d certainty="positive">nodule</d> is observed in the <a>upper right lobe S1</a>. <c>No significant difference</c> from a <t-test state="executed">CT</t-test> from <timex3 type="date">10 years ago</timex3>, doubt <d certainty="suspicious">benign nodules</d>. It seems to be equivalent to <d>T3</d> in the T classification.
<d certainty="suspicious">Concurrent pneumonia</d> is suspected due to <d certainty="positive">infiltrative shadows</d> observed in the <a>lower right lobe</a>.
<d certainty="suspicious">Metastasis</d> is suspected due to <f>numerous</f> <d certainty="positive">lymphadenopathy</d> observed in the <a>left supraclavicular fossa, bilateral mediastinum and the right hilar region</a>. It seems to be <d>equivalent to N3</d> in N classification.
<d certainty="negative">Pleural effusion</d> is not observed.
<d certainty="positive">Multiple nodules</d> are observed on <a>both sides of the breast, subcutaneously on the chest wall, liver, right adrenal gland and right side of the pelvic cavity</a>. Suspected <d certainty="suspicious">breast, subcutaneous, liver, right adrenal and right ovarian metastasis</d>. Unable to detect <d certainty="negative">osteolytic or condensing osteitis changes that are suspected of bone metastasis</d>. It seems to be equivalent to <d>M1c</d> in M classification.
Suspected <d certainty="suspicious">lymph node metastasis</d> due to <f>many</f> <d certainty="positive">swollen</d> <a>liver hilum</a> and <d certainty="positive">para-aortic lymph nodes</d>.
No <f>significant</f> abnormalities could be observed in the <a>gallbladder, pancreas, kidneys, or spleen</a>. <d certainty="negative">Ascites retention</d> is not observed.
In addition, no <f>significant</f> abnormality can be observed in the <a>≈image shown</a>.
</article>
<article id="71" title="12">
[<t-test state="executed">Routine chest CT</t-test>]
<f>Multiple</f> <d certainty="positive">nodules</d> observed in <a>both lungs</a>, indicating <d certainty="positive">lung cancer</d> and <a>bilateral</a> <d certainty="positive">multiple intrapulmonary metastases</d>.
No <d certainty="negative">significant lymph node tumors</d> can be identified.
<d certainty="positive">Sclerotic changes</d> observed in the <a>vertebra (Th3, 4, 8-11, L4, L5)</a>. These are likely to be <d certainty="positive">multiple metastases</d>.
No <d certainty="negative">metastasis</d> observed in <a>liver or adrenal glands</a>.
</article>
</articles>
</root>
